ubuntu.com 2019-06-26

# Data privacy | Ubuntu

Canonical collects personal information from you in a number of different ways. For example, when you download one of our products, receive services from us or use one of our websites (including [www.canonical.com](https://www.canonical.com/) and [www.ubuntu.com](https://www.ubuntu.com/)).

Full list of websites ›

At Canonical, we consider your privacy to be extremely important to us. These are the fundamental principles that we follow in relation to your personal information:

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it.
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to provide you with services, products, to comply with the law, or to protect our rights.
  * We don’t store personal information unless required for the on-going operation of services to you, to provide you with products, to comply with law or to protect our rights.
  * We will use personal information that you provide to us in accordance with this privacy policy.

Canonical Group Limited ( **“we”** , **“us”** and **“our”** ) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. Information collected for or on behalf of the Canonical group of companies will be the responsibility of Canonical Group Limited.

Full list of Canonical contracting entities ›

This policy (together with our terms of use and any other documents referred to on it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. By visiting a Canonical website you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy.

For the purpose of applicable data protection legislation, the data controller is Canonical Group limited (06870835) of 5th Floor, Blue Fin Building, 110 Southwark Street, London SE1 0SU.

Our nominated representative for all data privacy matters is Mrs Katherine Ollerhead, Director of Legal, Canonical Group Limited.

## Privacy notices

Specific details about personal data collection can be found in the relevant privacy notice:

  * Newsletter privacy notice ›
  * Webinar privacy notice ›
  * Online purchase privacy notice ›
  * Snap store privacy notice ›
  * Snapcraft NPS privacy notice ›
  * Contact us and enquiries privacy notice ›
  * Single sign on privacy notice ›
  * Partner Portal privacy notice ›
  * ESXi privacy notice ›

## Information we collect from you

  * **Information you give us**. This is information about you that you give us by filling in forms on a Canonical website or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise. It includes information you provide when you register to use our site, your login information where provided on a site or make a purchase on our site. It may includes the following: first name, last name; company name; company size; industry; job title; level; phone number; email address; state or province and country.
  * **Information about your visit**. This information includes the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL), clickstream to, through and from our site (including date and time, timezone, your geolocation), items you viewed or searched for, page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), methods used to browse away from the page.
  * **Information we receive from other sources**. This is information we receive about you if you use any of the other websites we operate or the other services we provide. In this case we will have informed you when we collected that data (through a Privacy notice) if we intend to share those data internally and combine it with data collected on this site. We will also have told you for what purpose we will share and combine your data. We are working closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, search information providers, credit reference agencies). We may notify you when we receive information about you from them and the purposes for which we intend to use that information.

## How information is collected from you

We may collect this information through the following routes:

### Websites

When you register to use certain parts of our websites, such as wikis, webinars or message boards, or register for free accounts, we may ask for personal information such as your full name, email address and a password. Please see the Privacy notice on collection for further details of how we will use your personal data.

### Chat rooms, forums and newsgroups

These are available to our community. Any information that you disclose in these areas becomes public information and may be recorded, archived and republished by anyone. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal information in such areas.

### Canonical products

When you register for services or purchase any product from Canonical, we may ask for information such as your email address, billing address, and credit card information. Credit card information is only used in processing your transaction. Please note that we may use a third party payment processing merchant to process your payments. Please see the terms and conditions of purchase and/or relevant Privacy notice for further information.

### Webinars

Some webinars are directly hosted by Canonical on our sites. Where a webinars is operated by a third party provider you will be directed to a third party website and the third party provider may collects information as part of the webinar registration process. This data will be collected in accordance with the third party provider’s terms and conditions. Please see “Links and third-party content” in the Terms and Conditions for further details.

### Non-personally identifying information

Canonical may collect non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Our purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how visitors use our websites and services. For further information about how we use cookies, see the “cookie” section below.

Please note that Canonical may also collect system information during installation of Ubuntu and on first login to Ubuntu. This system information is subject to a Legal Notice.

### Error reports

When you chose to send an error report, it includes a unique identifier for your computer. This identifier does not identify you, unless you (or someone acting on your behalf) discloses it separately. An error report may include personal information such as the state of programs that were running at the time. You can block future error reports from the privacy panel of System Settings.

### Ubuntu online accounts

When you use Ubuntu online accounts, your personal information is stored on your PC and it can be accessed by some applications. Further information can be found in a Legal Notice.

### Contacting us

If you contact us and provide us with information, we may keep a record of that correspondence and information.

## What do we do with your personal data

We may use your information in the following ways:

  * To authenticate access to certain features of our websites.
  * To contact you to respond to enquiries or to provide notices to you regarding your use of our websites or the provision of our services.
  * To provide services, products, process payment, and authenticate access (where required).
  * To analyse the performance or the appropriateness of products or services.
  * To comply with legal and regulatory requirements (including responding to court orders, subpoenas and to prevent crime). These special circumstances may require us to disclose personal information.
  * To contact you if your actions violate your agreement with us (if any).
  * To fix errors and analyse trends.
  * To study how anonymous users interact with our websites and services.
  * To market our products or services to you.

Unless you have notified us otherwise, Canonical may occasionally send you email to tell you about new features, solicit feedback, or just to keep you up to date with what’s going on. We may use various community websites (Launchpad Answers, Ubuntu Forums, blogs etc.) to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of information to a minimum. If you no longer wish to receive such communications from us, please follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in any of the communications, modify the communications preferences in your account or contact us using the contact details provided below.

## What are your rights?

You have the right to consent to our processing of personal data for marketing purposes and to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data.

You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [dataprotection@canonical.com](mailto:dataprotection@canonical.com) or by using the relevant contact us form.

Under the data protection legislation, you have the following rights. These consist of:

  * The right to be informed
  * The right of access
  * The right to rectification
  * The right to erasure
  * The right to restrict processing
  * The right to data portability
  * The right to object
  * Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling.

Each of these rights are supported by appropriate procedures within Canonical which allow the required action to be taken within the timescales stated in the applicable data protection legislation.

You can also ask us to stop using your information – the simplest way to do this is to withdraw your consent, which you can do at any time, either by clicking the unsubscribe link at the end of any newsletter, or by emailing, writing or telephoning us using the contact details above.

We keep your order information for so long as reasonably required in accordance with our record retention policy. Your personal information associated with the order will then be removed.

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

These timescales are shown in Table 1.

Data subject request | Timescale  
---|---  
The right to be informed | When data is collected (if supplied by data subject) or within one month (if not supplied by data subject)  
The right of access | One month  
The right to rectification | One month  
The right to erasure | Without undue delay  
The right to restrict processing | Without undue delay  
The right to data portability | One month  
The right to object | On receipt of objection  
Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling. | Not specified  
  
## Cookies

Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our site.

### What is a cookie?

A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard drive of your computer if you agree. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive.

We use the following cookies:

  * **Strictly necessary cookies**. These are cookies that are required for the operation of our website. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our website, use a shopping cart or make use of e-billing services.
  * **Analytical/performance cookies**. They allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our website when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way our website works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.
  * **Functionality cookies**. These are used to recognise you when you return to our website. This enables us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region).
  * **Targeting cookies**. These cookies record your visit to our website, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make our website and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.

You can find more information about the individual cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them in the table below:
